So what does A* do?
There's this algorithm,
I talked it up.
And it's kind of like Uniform-cost, but
it's kind of like Greedy, what's
it actually going to do?
Uniform-cost, we know on this search
tree diagram what it's going to do.
It's going to start at the top and
it's going to work downward.
It's going to be ragged because it's
going to go deeper in terms of number
of steps, where the actions are cheap,
but it's going to basically go from
top to bottom.
A* is going to go deep near the goals,
and shallower away from the goals.
But because it's hedging its bets and
because the heuristic is imperfect,
near the top of the tree it
will still do everything.
OK.
That's the shape of A* search.
And if you think about this, the way
we were looking at going in every
direction for a Uniform-cost search,
Uniform-cost search will expand
equally in all directions.
A*, however, is going to expand
mainly towards the goal.
It's not going to be like Greedy.
Let's take a look.
We go back to the empty maze.
Remember this is Greedy.
That was great.
I mean it's great when works, right?
Uniform-cost goes in every direction.
A* is going to do something
in between.
Here's A*.
It goes towards the goal but
it also goes a little bit
in the other direction.
Why?
The heuristic is saying you're
getting farther.
But the heuristic underestimates
the true distance.
So when you're almost to the goal in
one direction, the heuristic leaves
open the possibility that going to the
left is going to hit some wormhole or
something, and that going to the
left may actually be good.
Now, in this particular case it's not,
and that's because this heuristic is
imperfect, but A* hedges its bets to
the extent that the heuristic is a
lower bound.
So the worse the heuristic, the lower it
is as a lower bound, the more work
you're going to do just in order to
guarantee that you'll have optimality.